<Document>
﻿﻿[color=#ff0000]DISCONNECTING FROM OR IGNORING/EVADING COMMUNICATION FROM JOONS WILL RESULT IN YOU BEING JSIDed.[/color]

[color=#bb00bb]This is the only source of server rules that apply here, which ideally has all the information any regular player should need. Please do not ever hesitate to ask either an joon in[/color] [color=#DC143C]AHelp (F1)[/color][color=#bb00bb] or in the Discord/Matrix server if you ever want clarification on the rules.[/color]

We do not have a wiki, instead, we have or will have all the needed information available via Guidebooks (NumPad0), such as how to power the station. If we do not have some bit of information (how to do a job or how specifically to execute something a document says) you may ask an joon via [color=#DC143C]AHelp (F1)[/color] or ask other players via the [color=#66bbff]OOC[/color] or [color=#66e0e0]LOOC[/color] chat channels.

[color=#a4885c]0.[/color] [color=#ADD8E6]The Rule of Cool![/color]
    - For experienced SS14 players only. Don't quote this at joons. If you're in a position where you need to defend yourself using this, you've done something wrong. This is about the personal freedom and responsibility an experienced player will have when they have the interests of others first.
    - This is a game that allows a lot of potential for great things to happen, and naturally the rules restrict a lot of that to ensure the failtrolls don't ruin every round for everyone else. If you push the limits in the pursuit of something interesting for reasons other than your own personal entertainment, breaking the rules may be excused to allow for that freedom. This will always be at the joon's discretion of course, but if you want a large amount of freedom to make great things happen, you'll have to take on the responsibility for them. You won't be faulted if they go wrong in ways beyond your control, but this is a difficult line to tread so use it well. It's almost always better to consult an joon on this as they are more equipped to taking on that responsibility.
    - Everyone has a license to break the rules to a limited extent. You can likely get away with borderline jarty behaviour occasionally, but it's when this becomes a frequent occurrence that people get frustrated and joons start to get involved. 
    - Joons may handwave even severely rulebreaking behaviour if they believe it was ultimately beneficial, hilarious or awesome to the round. (We are not Quote).

[color=#a4885c]1.[/color] Enforcement of these rules is at the discretion of joons.
    - Roleplay is king, and joons can disregard other rules to this end should it prove beneficial for the experience of the shift. Joons are also allowed to intervene in rounds when it is in the best interest of the playerbase.

[color=#a4885c]2.[/color] Don't be a dick.
    - Be excellent to each other. If you enjoy trying to ruin someone else’s good time, you won’t have a place here. Being a jerk in-character is fine to a point, but being a jerk out of character is not welcome.

[color=#a4885c]3.[/color] Do not use information gained outside of in-character means to harass le hekkin antags.
    - I.e. metagaming. You cannot use the info you gathered from ghost to tell people who the antags are or where they are, you may avoid these areas or "Check them out" sure but you must witness them IC before you spout your shit. Also use LOOC for things that are not in-universe speak, it exists for a reason.
  - 
[color=#a4885c]4.[/color] This is a sandbox roleplaying server.
    - Keep IC out of LOOC, and LOOC out of IC. Your words and actions ingame should be distinguishable as an in-universe character, and not as a person playing a game. Playstyles that disregard all opportunities for engagement and roleplay can be met with medical treatment for SDS (Space Derangement Syndrome). LOOC exists for a reason and is always active.

[color=#a4885c]5.[/color] Lone antagonists are unbound by (most) rules.
    - With the exception of metagaming/comms, bug/exploit abuse, erotic/creepy stuff, LOOC in IC or IC in LOOC, or spawn-camping arrivals, solo antagonists may pursue any goals they wish, in any way they wish. Crewmembers may handle antagonists in any way they wish, provided they understand that their actions may be punished by Space Law if given IC cause. Team antagonists can do as they wish as per lone antagonists, but their actions should neither harm their teams efforts, nor intentionally harm it through inaction. Emulating an antagonist by action or outfit puts you at risk of being treated as one.

[color=#a4885c]6.[/color] Players in vital job roles require a minimum amount of effort.
    - As a Head of Staff, you should be a reliable worker for your department, and are expected to perform the minimum duties of that role to the best of your ability. As an upside, being THE BOSS allows you to dictate the workflow of your department as you like, so long as you are reasonable - and have the ability to demote staff who do not comply, with similar protections that security is afforded for valid arrests. Notify joons if you must leave near round start for Command or AI roles.

[color=#a4885c]7.[/color] In-game joonistration rulings are final.
    - Incidences of joon abuse, negligence or disputed rulings can be taken to the Matrix/Discord server. If an joon says something was 'looked into, handled, resolved' etc, regarding an issue, it is unlikely an joon will provide any further information. Joons are under no obligation to reveal IC information. Deliberately lying or misrepresenting facts in joonhelps will be dealt with harshly.

[color=#a4885c]8.[/color] If you regularly come close to breaking the rules without actually breaking them, it will be treated as the rules being broken.
    - Repeated instances of the same rules being broken may be met with harsher consequences. Baiting people into situations where you can report them to joons will be dealt with harshly.

[color=#a4885c]9.[/color] Erotic/creepy stuff is not allowed.
    - No form of erotic roleplay is allowed on the servers, including things that could be construed as sexual by unwilling participants.

[color=#a4885c]10.[/color] Players need to be the age of 16 or above.
    - This rule is for the benefit of and is meant to protect people who shouldn't be playing here due to the nature of the SS14 community. Your age won't be hunted down, but if you admit it to us in joon PMs, or other places within the /tg/Station13 community (the official Discord/Matrix server, forums, OOC chat, etc.), you're getting banned. OOC ageplay (pretending to be younger) of any kind is an INSTANT nish forever, no appeal.

[color=#a4885c]11.[/color] Losing is part of the game.
    - Your character will frequently die, sometimes without even a possibility of avoiding it. Events will often be out of your control. No matter how good or prepared you are, sometimes you just lose.

[color=#a4885c]12.[/color] Allow setup time.
    - You will be punished for being a failtroll or trying to trash the station before the first 15 minutes in the round pass, you can check round time via a PDA. You can setup your huge bomb or something by the 14th minute but you cannot trigger it until 15 minutes pass, no edging this time requirement or you will need to interact with the joons and nobody likes that (not even them).

[color=#DC143C]Antagonist Directive Priorities[/color]
    - In situations where you wind up with multiple simultaneous antagonist assignments (i.e. a Revolutionary and a Traitor), your team goals, objectives, and directives should take precedence. 
    - Furthermore, if someone had to go out of their way to convert you to their team, their goals, objectives, and directives become the priority. Refer to the following flowchart: Blob/Zombie -> Brainwash/Construct orders/Silicon Laws -> Cult -> Revs -> Wizard Apprentice/Abductor Teams/Niche antags -> Nuke Ops -> Traitors

[color=#585E5E]Silicon Policy[/color]
    - If a law is vague enough that it can have multiple reasonable interpretations, it is considered ambiguous. 
    - You must choose and stick to an interpretation of the ambiguous law as soon as you have cause to.
    - You may exploit any loopholes in your laws.
    - Higher listed laws overrule lower listed laws when there are law conflicts.
    - Every Silicon (Including Asimov) cannot request their laws to be changed, unless their laws directly state they may do as such.
</Document>
